<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Rachit Gupta</title><link href="http://r4chi7.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://r4chi7.github.io/feeds/tag/libreoffce.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://r4chi7.github.io/</id><updated>2014-06-03T00:42:05+05:30</updated><entry><title>GSoC - Improve Usability of Personas - Introduction</title><link href="http://r4chi7.github.io/2014/06/gsoc-improve-usability-of-personas-introduction/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-03T00:42:05+05:30</updated><author><name>Rachit Gupta</name></author><id>tag:r4chi7.github.io,2014-06-03:2014/06/gsoc-improve-usability-of-personas-introduction/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I got selected for 2014's Google Summer of Code to work for LibreOffice. I will be working on the &lt;a href="https://wiki.documentfoundation.org/Development/GSoC/Ideas#Improve_usability_of_Personas"&gt;Improve Usability of Personas idea&lt;/a&gt; this summer. As my &lt;a href="https://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/project/details/google/gsoc2014/r4chi7/5757334940811264"&gt;proposal&lt;/a&gt; indicates, the task will be to improve the UI of the Personalization dialog and the implementation behind it. The Personalization dialog allows users to select and apply &lt;a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/themes/"&gt;Mozilla's Personas&lt;/a&gt; to their copy of Libreoffice. The dialog can be accessed by &lt;em&gt;Tools -&amp;gt; Options -&amp;gt; Personalization -&amp;gt; Select Theme&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Select Persona Dialog" src="/images/lo-personas.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current implementation requires the user to browse through the themes in their browser, select the theme of their liking, copy and paste the URL in the dialog, and wait till the theme is downloaded and applied. &lt;strong&gt;Too much work&lt;/strong&gt; IMO. My work during the summer will be to make this process easy and intuitive for the users. Also, the current implementation parses the HTML from the personas page to get the details. Following are the main sub tasks for this summer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow users to search for themes in the dialog with the help of &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/addons.mozilla.org_%28AMO%29_API_Developers%27_Guide/The_generic_AMO_API#search"&gt;Mozilla's AMO API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow users to select their favorite theme from the dialog itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make the searching and downloading of themes run in a separate thread so the UI does not hang awkwardly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow users(read designers) to apply their self made themes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solve some Personas related bugs/enhancement requests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Possibly&lt;/em&gt;, do some pagination so the users can browse more themes in the dialog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With some research, and a lot of help from my mentor, &lt;a href="http://holesovsky.blogspot.in/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jan Holesovsky&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the work is under progress. Keep watching this space for more about the progress!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers to the summer of 2014!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="gsoc"></category><category term="libreoffce"></category><category term="foss"></category></entry></feed>