<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Rachit Gupta</title><link href="http://blog.rachitgupta.in/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.rachitgupta.in/feeds/tag/libreoffice.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.rachitgupta.in/</id><updated>2014-06-03T00:00:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>GSoC - Improve Usability of Personas - Introduction</title><link href="http://blog.rachitgupta.in/2014/06/gsoc-improve-usability-of-personas-introduction/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-03T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Rachit Gupta</name></author><id>tag:blog.rachitgupta.in,2014-06-03:2014/06/gsoc-improve-usability-of-personas-introduction/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Libreoffice 4.0 introduced the concept of using &lt;a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/themes/"&gt;Personas&lt;/a&gt;. The users can apply themes to their office suite! Since then, there has been an idea on the &lt;a href="https://wiki.documentfoundation.org/Development/GSoC/Ideas#Improve_usability_of_Personas"&gt;GSoC Page wiki&lt;/a&gt; to improve the usability of the selection of the themes process. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, what improvements? The current implementation requires the user to browse through the themes in their browser, select the theme of their liking, copy and paste the URL in the dialog, and wait till the theme is downloaded and applied. &lt;strong&gt;Too much work&lt;/strong&gt; IMO. My work during the summer will be to make this process easy and intuitive for the users. Also, the current implementation parses the HTML from the personas page to get the details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Select Persona Dialog" src="/images/lo-personas.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href="https://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/project/details/google/gsoc2014/r4chi7/5757334940811264"&gt;proposal&lt;/a&gt; for the idea got selected and I'll be working on this idea this summer. My aim is to make the process of searching for themes and applying them, easy and intuitive for the users, alongwith making the process work better and faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following are the main tasks for this summer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow users to search for themes in the dialog with the help of &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/addons.mozilla.org_%28AMO%29_API_Developers%27_Guide/The_generic_AMO_API#search"&gt;Mozilla's AMO API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow users to select their favorite theme from the dialog itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make the searching and downloading of themes run in a separate thread so the UI does not hang awkwardly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow users(read designers) to apply their self made themes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solve some Personas related bugs/enhancement requests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Possibly&lt;/em&gt;, do some pagination so the users can browse more themes in the dialog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With some research, and a lot of help from my mentor, &lt;a href="http://holesovsky.blogspot.in/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jan Holesovsky&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the work is under progress. Keep watching this space for more about the progress!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers to the summer of 2014!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="gsoc"></category><category term="libreoffice"></category><category term="foss"></category></entry><entry><title>From Zero Knowledge About Open Source to GSoC</title><link href="http://blog.rachitgupta.in/2014/06/from-zero-knowledge-about-open-source-to-gsoc/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Rachit Gupta</name></author><id>tag:blog.rachitgupta.in,2014-06-01:2014/06/from-zero-knowledge-about-open-source-to-gsoc/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It all started 2 years ago when we heard about a senior(&lt;a href="http://blog.rishab.in"&gt;Rishab Arora&lt;/a&gt;) doing his Google Summer of Code. At that time, I didn't know much about it. So, I started researching about it. Obviously I knew what open source softwares were, but never did I imagine the terminology will change the way I look at softwares!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided I will do my GSoC as well. I started with KDE, and chose &lt;a href="http://www.calligra-suite.org"&gt;Calligra&lt;/a&gt; as my project. I started working on a &lt;a href="http://community.kde.org/KDE/Junior_Jobs"&gt;Junior Job&lt;/a&gt;. I successfully managed to push a &lt;a href="https://git.reviewboard.kde.org/r/109514"&gt;patch&lt;/a&gt;! That was one of the best feelings I've ever had! Then came the time for GSoC, and down goes my laptop's processor! Dreams were shattered. Hopes were lost. I couldn't participate in 2013's GSoC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then, I realized it was not the end of life. I was fascinated by &lt;a href="http://www.libreoffice.org"&gt;LibreOffice&lt;/a&gt;, with the fact they provide almost all the features of Microsoft Office with &lt;strong&gt;zero&lt;/strong&gt; times the cost (something * 0 = 0). And it was Open Source! I decided to contribute to this fantastic software suite. I didn't have GSoC in mind then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sheer amount of code in the repository was too much for me. But, the community was really helpful, and I finally managed to solve my first &lt;a href="https://wiki.documentfoundation.org/Development/Easy_Hacks"&gt;Easy Hack&lt;/a&gt; after a lot of changes! I managed to solve 3 easy hacks in 2 months:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://gerrit.libreoffice.org/#/c/7514"&gt;fdo#52461&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://gerrit.libreoffice.org/#/c/8163"&gt;fdo#74913&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://gerrit.libreoffice.org/#/c/8364"&gt;fdo#74064&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then I decided to go for Google Summer of Code. I worked hard, faced some difficulties, but finally I managed to submit my &lt;a href="https://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/project/details/google/gsoc2014/r4chi7/5757334940811264"&gt;proposal&lt;/a&gt;. And as you might have guessed, I got selected! :-D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If any of you wishes to know more about my work, keep watching this space! I'll be writing more about it soon. Feel free to drop an e-mail at &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;&amp;#114;&amp;#97;&amp;#99;&amp;#104;&amp;#105;&amp;#116;&amp;#103;&amp;#117;&amp;#112;&amp;#116;&amp;#97;&amp;#49;&amp;#55;&amp;#57;&amp;#50;&amp;#64;&amp;#103;&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#46;&amp;#99;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;"&gt;&amp;#114;&amp;#97;&amp;#99;&amp;#104;&amp;#105;&amp;#116;&amp;#103;&amp;#117;&amp;#112;&amp;#116;&amp;#97;&amp;#49;&amp;#55;&amp;#57;&amp;#50;&amp;#64;&amp;#103;&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#46;&amp;#99;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="gsoc"></category><category term="libreoffice"></category><category term="foss"></category></entry></feed>